Register of the Ob"edinenie russkikh v Marokko Records, 1918-1965
Hoover Institution Archives
Ob"edinenie russkikh v Marokko Records
1918-1965
83036
Hoover Institution Archives
2 manuscript boxes (0.8 linear feet)
Correspondence, memoranda, reports, lists, and financial records, relating to activities of the Russian émigré community and Russian Orthodox Church in Morocco, primarily in Casablanca.
Ob"edinenie russkikh v Marokko
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Materials were acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1983
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Scope and Contents note
Correspondence, memoranda, reports, lists, and financial records, relating to activities of the Russian émigré community and Russian Orthodox Church in Morocco, primarily in Casablanca.
Biographical/Historical note
Russian émigré organization.
Russkaia pravoslavnaia tserkov' zagranitsei; Africa.; Morocco.; Russia.; Russians--Morocco.
- CORRESPONDENCE, 1931-1961 (Box 1)
  Scope and Contents note
  Arranged by category of correspondent.
  - General
    - Undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - 1931-1940 (Folder 2)
    - 1943-1949 (Folder 3)
    - 1950-1961 (Folder 4)
  - French authorities, 1931-1953 (Folder 5)
  - Synod of Russian Church Abroad, 1949-1962 (Folder 6)
- MEMBERSHIP, 1931-1957 (Box 1)
  Includes applications, records of dues payments, membership lists.
  - Applications (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Dues (Folder 8)
  - Lists (Folder 9)
- MINUTES OF MEETINGS AND PROTOCOLS, 1931-1957.
  - Proxy votes (Box 1, Folder 10)
- STATUTES, 1918-1937 (Box 1)
  Includes drafts of organization statutes in Fench and Russian.
  - Statutes (Box 1, Folder 11)
- SUBJECT FILE, 1944-1965 (Box 2)
  Clippings, correspondence, petitions and printed matter, arranged alphabetically by topic.
  - Cemetery, correspondence, 1952-1965 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Construction of church in Casablanca, 1950-1957 (Folder 2)
    - Architect's plans, financial reports
  - Russian Church in the U.S.S.R. Clippings and excerpts from newspapers, 1947-1950 (Folder 3)
  - Schism within the organization, 1957-1958
    - Legal correspondence and petitions in French (Folder 4)
    - Miscellaneous material in Russian (Folder 5)
  - Trushnovich, Aleksandr, kidnapping. Correspondence, 1954 (Folder 6)
  - U.S.S.R., collection of funds in Morocco for aid to Russian children, 1944 (Folder 7)
  - Miscellany. Graphs, invitations, parish reports, 1950-1958 (Folder 8)